<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on HGComputational Journal Club</title>
    <link>https://xinhe-lab.github.io/journal-club/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on HGComputational Journal Club</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>gaow@uchicago.edu (Gao Wang)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gaow@uchicago.edu (Gao Wang)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2017 Copyright Human Genetics Computational Group | The University of Chicago</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://xinhe-lab.github.io/journal-club/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Variation in Gene Expression Modulates the Severity of Mutant Phenotypes</title>
      <link>https://xinhe-lab.github.io/journal-club/20180206-victoria-2015-cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gaow@uchicago.edu (Gao Wang)</author>
      <guid>https://xinhe-lab.github.io/journal-club/20180206-victoria-2015-cell/</guid>
      <description>Biological question Mutation in monogenic disease can cause disease phenotype at various level of severity.
For instance, cystic fiberosis (CF) is caused by a single gene, CFTR, the homozygous individuals with exactly the same allele $\delta$F508 present a wide range of clinical symptoms. It is due to &amp;laquo;modifier genes&amp;raquo;, MBL2 and TGF-$\beta$.
Such observation is general in many Mendelian diseases. Namely, the disease is predictable but the severity of it is highly unknown due to the variation of genetic background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulatory elements: Putting enhancers into context</title>
      <link>https://xinhe-lab.github.io/journal-club/20171205-burgess-2016-nrg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gaow@uchicago.edu (Gao Wang)</author>
      <guid>https://xinhe-lab.github.io/journal-club/20171205-burgess-2016-nrg/</guid>
      <description>Regulatory elements: Putting enhancers into context
Principle of suboptimization The enhancer consists of low-affinity TF binding sites in a suboptimal syntax, in terms of flanking nucleotides and spacing between the sites. Optimizing the TF binding affinities can lead to ectopic expression.
Experiment In sea squirt, 15 synthetic enhancers consisting of 2 ETS binding sites and a ZicL binding site. Only 2 show activities. Further manipulation confirm key roles for binding site orientation, spacing and flanking nucleotides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial reconstruction of single-cell gene expression data</title>
      <link>https://xinhe-lab.github.io/journal-club/20171205-seurat-2015-nbt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gaow@uchicago.edu (Gao Wang)</author>
      <guid>https://xinhe-lab.github.io/journal-club/20171205-seurat-2015-nbt/</guid>
      <description>Problem  infer spatial locations of various cell types which will determine the cell fate and behavior
 RNA staining only assays a small number of transcripts and RNA-seq can measure the global gene expression, but separates the cells from their native spatial context.
 they develop Seurat to localize the cells by integrating single cell RNA-seq data and in situ RNA patterns.
  Modeling Overview Figure 1 gives the overview of the method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read-n-share</title>
      <link>https://xinhe-lab.github.io/journal-club/20171129-uchg-compbio-jc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gaow@uchicago.edu (Gao Wang)</author>
      <guid>https://xinhe-lab.github.io/journal-club/20171129-uchg-compbio-jc/</guid>
      <description>In summer 2017 during one of the Xin He lab reading group session we came up with the notion of crowdsourcing the efforts of reading papers. The gist is that we should figure out a way to not only share our literature reading notes, but also engage in discussions / debates if there are multiple people interested in the same paper.
We were excited about the idea. But how do we go about implementing it?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>